[
  {
    "question": "The tectonic plates form?",
    "optionOne": "The listhophere.",
    "optionTwo": "The asthenosphere.",
    "optionThree": "The paleosphere.",
    "correctAnswer": "The listhophere."
  },
  {
    "question": "Except tectonic plates boundaries, where can we find volcanoes?",
    "optionOne": "In hotzones.",
    "optionTwo": "In hotspots.",
    "optionThree": "At subduction zones.",
    "correctAnswer": "In hotspots."
  },
  {
    "question": "At what rate tectonic plates progress?",
    "optionOne": "Between 3 and 5cms a year.",
    "optionTwo": "Between 5 and 8cms a year.",
    "optionThree": "Between 8 and 10cms a year.",
    "correctAnswer": "Between 3 and 5cms a year."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a tectonic boundary type?",
    "optionOne": "Divergent.",
    "optionTwo": "Transform.",
    "optionThree": "Adjacent.",
    "correctAnswer": "Adjacent."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a tectonic boundary type?",
    "optionOne": "Opposite.",
    "optionTwo": "Convergent.",
    "optionThree": "Lateral.",
    "correctAnswer": "Convergent."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which volcano type creates hudge crater?",
    "optionOne": "Composite volcano.",
    "optionTwo": "Dome volcano.",
    "optionThree": "Caldera volcano.",
    "correctAnswer": "Caldera volcano."
  },
  {
    "question": "What characterize volcano types?",
    "optionOne": "The lava flow.",
    "optionTwo": "The slope angle or steepness.",
    "optionThree": "The explosion's violence.",
    "correctAnswer": "The lava flow."
  },
  {
    "question": "What characterized volcanic eruption in detailed classification?",
    "optionOne": "Seismologic activity and ground composition.",
    "optionTwo": "Volcanic activity type and location.",
    "optionThree": "Tectonic plates names that created them.",
    "correctAnswer": "Volcanic activity type and location."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a type erruption?",
    "optionOne": "Hawaiian.",
    "optionTwo": "Pelean.",
    "optionThree": "Italian.",
    "correctAnswer": "Italian."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is the most destructive and intense volcanic erruption?",
    "optionOne": "Plinian.",
    "optionTwo": "Icelandic.",
    "optionThree": "Stombolian.",
    "correctAnswer": "Plinian."
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of glass lava can create?",
    "optionOne": "Vesicles.",
    "optionTwo": "Obsidian.",
    "optionThree": "Basalt.",
    "correctAnswer": "Obsidian."
  },
  {
    "question": "What can create volcanic chain?",
    "optionOne": "earthquakes.",
    "optionTwo": "Magma chambers.",
    "optionThree": "Hotspots.",
    "correctAnswer": "Hotspots."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the hottest lava temperature?",
    "optionOne": "About 1100 celsius degree.",
    "optionTwo": "About 800 celsius degree.",
    "optionThree": "About 100 celsius degree.",
    "correctAnswer": "About 1100 celsius degree."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a plume composed of?",
    "optionOne": "Volcanic water.",
    "optionTwo": "Volcanic ash.",
    "optionThree": "Volcanic smoke.",
    "correctAnswer": "Volcanic ash."
  },
  {
    "question": "How much of the earth surface rainforests cover?",
    "optionOne": "4%.",
    "optionTwo": "12%.",
    "optionThree": "18%.",
    "correctAnswer": "4%."
  },
  {
    "question": "How large is the canopy layer?",
    "optionOne": "About 3 meters.",
    "optionTwo": "About 6 meters.",
    "optionThree": "About 9 meters.",
    "correctAnswer": "About 6 meters."
  },
  {
    "question": "What layer of the rainforest is the darkest?",
    "optionOne": "The Canopy Layer.",
    "optionTwo": "The Understory Layer.",
    "optionThree": "The Forest Floor.",
    "correctAnswer": "The Forest Floor."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the rainforest layer is home to the most animals?",
    "optionOne": "Canopy.",
    "optionTwo": "Understory.",
    "optionThree": "Forest floor.",
    "correctAnswer": "Canopy."
  },
  {
    "question": "What specialization flowers of the understory develop?",
    "optionOne": "Long stem.",
    "optionTwo": "Strong sent.",
    "optionThree": "Light color.",
    "correctAnswer": "Strong sent."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is specialization?",
    "optionOne": "The amount of different species in one place.",
    "optionTwo": "The type of food a species is attracted to.",
    "optionThree": "Strategies and innovations develop by species to survive.",
    "correctAnswer": "Strategies and innovations develop by species to survive."
  },
  {
    "question": "How much of the species rainforest host is likely to be lost evey decade?",
    "optionOne": "None.",
    "optionTwo": "Between 5 and 10%.",
    "optionThree": "More than 50%.",
    "correctAnswer": "Between 5 and 10%."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why plants of the rainforest developed leaves with pointy tips?",
    "optionOne": "so the wind doesn't blow the leaves away.",
    "optionTwo": "So the water doesn't stay on the leaves avoiding the development of fungus.",
    "optionThree": "To fight aginst insects that eat their leaves.",
    "correctAnswer": "So the water doesn't stay on the leaves avoiding the development of fungus."
  },
  {
    "question": "how are called the pointy tips leaves that plants of the rainforest developed?",
    "optionOne": "Drip tips.",
    "optionTwo": "Dry tips.",
    "optionThree": "Hydro tips.",
    "correctAnswer": "Drip tips."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is foliage?",
    "optionOne": "The fact of having no leaves.",
    "optionTwo": "The leafy parts of a tree or a plant.",
    "optionThree": "The layer of leaves fallen on the forest floor.",
    "correctAnswer": "The leafy parts of a tree or a plant."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is biodiversity?",
    "optionOne": "What is common in all species.",
    "optionTwo": "The science of life and living organisms.",
    "optionThree": "A measure of the diversity of species.",
    "correctAnswer": "A measure of the diversity of species."
  },
  {
    "question": "How long can live the Brazil nut tree?",
    "optionOne": "120 years.",
    "optionTwo": "600 years.",
    "optionThree": "1000 years.",
    "correctAnswer": "1000 years."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are epiphytes?",
    "optionOne": "Plants that only grow on other trees.",
    "optionTwo": "Plants that eat insects.",
    "optionThree": "Plants that grow in an epi shape.",
    "correctAnswer": "Plants that only grow on other trees."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the food chain?",
    "optionOne": "It describes the way fruits are attached to trees.",
    "optionTwo": "It describes how different organisms eat each other.",
    "optionThree": "The quatity of food an animal eat in a periode of time.",
    "correctAnswer": "It describes how different organisms eat each other."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is an ebb tide?",
    "optionOne": "When the tide is going towards the low tide.",
    "optionTwo": "When the level of the water is still.",
    "optionThree": "When the tide is going towards the hight tide.",
    "correctAnswer": "When the tide is going towards the low tide."
  },
  {
    "question": "How is called the low point of the tide?",
    "optionOne": "The down tide.",
    "optionTwo": "The low tide.",
    "optionThree": "The bottom tide.",
    "correctAnswer": "The low tide."
  },
  {
    "question": "What kind of energy is transmitted by a wave?",
    "optionOne": "Elastic energy.",
    "optionTwo": "Thermal energy.",
    "optionThree": "kinetic energy.",
    "correctAnswer": "kinetic energy."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are called waves that appear without being expected and of unexpected size?",
    "optionOne": "Rogue waves.",
    "optionTwo": "Hidden waves.",
    "optionThree": "Random waves.",
    "correctAnswer": "Rogue waves."
  },
  {
    "question": "Who produce the most oxygen on earth?",
    "optionOne": "Trees.",
    "optionTwo": "Phytoplankton.",
    "optionThree": "Zooplankton.",
    "correctAnswer": "Phytoplankton."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is evaporation?",
    "optionOne": "Water changing state from liquid to vapor.",
    "optionTwo": "Water changing state from solid to liquid.",
    "optionThree": "Water changing state from solid to vapor.",
    "correctAnswer": "Water changing state from liquid to vapor."
  },
  {
    "question": "How is called the zone defined by the tidal range?",
    "optionOne": "Intertidal zone.",
    "optionTwo": "Midtidal zone.",
    "optionThree": "Ecotidal zone.",
    "correctAnswer": "Intertidal zone."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following facts is false?",
    "optionOne": "More than 80% of the ocean is unexplored.",
    "optionTwo": "Water takes about 1000 years to travel all the way around the globe.",
    "optionThree": "Less than 60% of the total water on Earth is in the Ocean.",
    "correctAnswer": "Less than 60% of the total water on Earth is in the Ocean."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the fish leaving on earth 300 million years ago and still swiming the ocean?",
    "optionOne": "The coelacanth.",
    "optionTwo": "The cyprinus carpio.",
    "optionThree": "The oncorhyncus keta.",
    "correctAnswer": "The coelacanth."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is deposition?",
    "optionOne": "Water changing state from solid to liquid.",
    "optionTwo": "Water changing state from vapor to solid.",
    "optionThree": "Water changing state from liquid to solid.",
    "correctAnswer": "Water changing state from vapor to solid."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the largest living organism on earth that can be seen from the Moon?",
    "optionOne": "The Blue Whale.",
    "optionTwo": "The Polar Bear.",
    "optionThree": "The Great Barrier Reef.",
    "correctAnswer": "The Great Barrier Reef."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is oceanology?",
    "optionOne": "The study of Earth surface.",
    "optionTwo": "The study of the ocean.",
    "optionThree": "Whom study the ocean.",
    "correctAnswer": "The study of the ocean."
  },
  {
    "question": "What causes tides?",
    "optionOne": "Gravitational forces.",
    "optionTwo": "Waves.",
    "optionThree": "Ocean currents.",
    "correctAnswer": "Gravitational forces."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the deepest part of the ocean at more than 10 kms?",
    "optionOne": "The Philippine Trench.",
    "optionTwo": "The Tonga Trench.",
    "optionThree": "The Marina Trench.",
    "correctAnswer": "The Marina Trench."
  }
]